KEVIN K. NAIK

Tel: (M) 09825976414
E-mail: kevinnaik@yahoo.com
Website: www.kevinnaik.info

PERSONAL SUMMARY

Highly motivated, committed and hardworking individual with flexible attitude to adapt to challenges when they arise and ability to handle change in a positive manner.

I have a clear, logical mind with a practical approach to problem solving. A team player with proven ability to get along with both work colleagues and senior managers.

All my work experience and academic achievements to date now make me feel fully prepared to become a professional.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Silver Oak College of Engineering and Technology, Ahmedabad, India Head Automation and Robotics Assistant Professor in Mechanical Department

[Jan 2015 - Present]

INGITE (Incubation Centre), **S4** (Student Start-up Support System) Chapter, **Robotics Lab** in-charge: handling are major responsibilities undertaken. Duties related to INGITE are to set up INGITE's Labs, carrying out workshops and lecture series for same. Mentoring students and helping them to finalize their idea and develop their prototypes in S4. The challenge was to restart the Robotics lab which had been shut for last 8 Months. I have successfully started it again and it is working efficiently now. Also help students finish their projects on technology like raspberry pi, Arduno. Moreover, few extra duties like senior supervisor, admission committee also handled.

Skills:- Leadership, Team work, Teaching, Programming, General management, Mentoring. Tools:- Python, Open CV, Matlab, MS Office

L&T Infotech Ltd Internship

[Aug - Oct 2015]

Working as intern in NUI Lab of Technology Office on technologies like .Net Gadgeteer, Leap motion and Kinect for developing Internet of Things. Pushing and extracting data over cloud to control actuators.

Skills:- Coding, Researching, Blogging, Meetings, Presentations Tools:- .Net micro framework, C#, Microsoft Azure

Abellon Clean Energy Limited, Ahmedabad, India MANAGEMENT TRAINEE

[April-Sept 2012]

Responsible for new technology purchases and maintenance arrangements. Assisted a team that ensures health and safety at work place. Managed a project of installing shop floor machinery utilizing the knowledge gained from hands on experience in similar other project.

Duties:

- Analyzing and specifying the requirements of new technologies, identifying suitable suppliers, gain
 approvals from higher management for the purchase, administer the purchase process and establish
 the most appropriate maintenance contracts.
- Liaising with in-house maintenance team and technology vendors for ongoing maintenance issues.
- Involved in assembling shop floor machinery along with a team of engineers from offshore machine manufacturer.

 Handled a challenging project to install Destoner machine to filter stones from raw material in welldesigned plant.

Skill:- Team Management, Vendor Management, Installation, Observation, Monitoring, Costing and Evaluation, Project Management.

Tools:- Primavera, AutoCAD, Microsoft Excel

Inifinite institute Private Limited, Ahmedabad, India TECHNOLOGY TUTOR

[2011-2012]

Worked as visiting Tutor and Mentor for 20 students teaching various technology related subjects as well as mentoring them during their workshop and project activities. All these students achieved very good results in their exams and received full compliments from their project work with industry.

Skills:- Programming, Teaching

Tools:- C/C++, PHP

ACADEMIC QUALIFICATION

MSc Robotics

King's College London, University of London

[2012-2013]

Project: (Acedamic) Developed a New Algorithm for finding Indentation Depth of Soft Tissue

Probe was design and developed for the project. A new algorithm develop was real time and could find depth. The conclusion was drawn based on experiments carried out on chicken meat and pork liver.

Skills :- Designing, Programming, Data Analysis, Manufacturing, Writing

Tools :- Matlab, AutoCAD, Solidworks, 3D Printer, SPSS, LaTex

MBA Technology Management with major in Operations and Project Management CEPT University. Ahmedabad. India

[2010-2012]

Research Thesis: New Product Development Cycle improvement using Virtual Reality

The research was carried out to study whether virtual reality can be used in new product development cycle in manufacturing, if yes than up to what level. *Achieved best thesis awards for the work.*

Project: (Industry) Kemrock Export Limited, Vadodara, India

To study the different production process like Moulding, Pultrusion, Filament winding, Pipe. To study and learn the process planning.

Project: (Academic) Designed and Prototype of Innovative Rice Thresher

This was done for the for lower end farmers to reduce the effort that went into manual threshing and to thus increase their productivity. The effort was appreciated by the NIF (Dr. Anil Gupta), Dr. Vakil (Vise chancellor of CEPT University) and widely covered in the local newspapers. *Patent is pending for the product.*

Skill:- Research Methodology, Data Acquisition, Literature Analysis, Statistics, Manufacturing Process,

Tools:- SPSS, Microsoft Excel, Stand Drill, CNC Machining, Cutting

Bachelor of Technology Mechatronics

U.V. Patel College of Engineering, Ganpat University, Gujarat, India

[2006-2010]

Project: (Academic) Robotic Arm

The robot was used to pick and place objects, and in painting and other applications. The microcontroller was used to control the DC servo motors. It was a multipurpose device where the two arms could work in different directions.

WORKSHOP/ ORGANIZATIONAL EXPERIENCE/ EXTRA-CURRICULAR ACTIVITIES

- Under Incubation centre organized and manage various workshops, Boot camps and lecture series.
- Organized various workshop of Robotics at Silver Oak Group of Institutes.
- Incubator Training Capacity Building Workshop attended at CIIE
- International Conference on Design Thinking attended at GTU
- Founder and chairman of Skyrock Club (Technical and Non-technical club).
- Worked as the coordinator of various technical and non-technical events held at college by different industry
- C/ C++ course, developed new programs for the college manual.
- Hosted and participated in various technical and non technical events at national level during college.
- Active member of college as well as professional team of Cricket, Volleyball and Basketball in India and UK.

PERSONAL INFORMATION

Date of birth : 9 August 1988 Preferred Location : Anywhere

Languages known : English, Hindi and Gujarati

Ahmedabad (Kevin K. Naik)